Inventory of the Jude Wanniski papers, 1965-2006
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and Writings, 1974-2005; 23-27
  - "Trial by Press: James B. Stewart vs. Michael Milken,", 1991 October 9
    - Correspondence and mailing list (Folder 26: 11)
    - Typescript and printed copy (Folder 26: 12)
  - "Praise for Bush's Gold Initiative," New York Times, 1992 October 4 (Folder 26: 13)
  - "Thinking Black,", 1994 February 22 (Folder 26: 14)
  - "Trade War with Japan?,", 1994 March 4 (Folder 26: 15)
  - "Clinton, Whitewater, China and Korea,", 1994 March 22 (Folder 26: 16)
  - "Crisis Atmosphere,", 1994 May 9 (Folder 26: 17)
  - "Bringing the GOP's Agenda up to Date," Washington Times, 1994 August 9 (Folder 26: 18)
  - "Iraq: Send for Colin Powell,", 1994 October 11 (Folder 26: 19)
  - "Daddy State, Mommy State,", 1995 May 30 (Folder 26: 20)
  - "Hoover's Heirs," New York Times, 1996 August 6 (Folder 26: 21)
  - "In Defense of Saddam Hussein,", 1996 September 3 (Folder 26: 22)
  - "The High-Tech Babies and Capital Gains,", 1997 July 21 (Folder 26: 23)
  - "Letter to Malaysia's Deputy Premier, Anwar Ibrahim,", 1997 October 14 (Folder 26: 24)
  - "The Asian Flu,", 1997 October 23 (Folder 26: 25)
  - "Two Kinds of Deflation,", 1997 November (Folder 26: 26)
  - "Slippery Slope in Iraq,", 1997 November 12 (Folder 26: 27)
  - "Iraq, a Manufactured Crisis,", 1997 November 17 (Folder 26: 28)
  - The Last Race of the 20th Century, 1997 December (Folder 26: 29-31)
  - "The Optimum Price of Gold," Wall Street Journal, 1998 January 7 (Folder 27: 1)
  - "At Last, Greenspan,", 1998 September 24 (Folder 27: 2)
  - Article on Robert Mundell and gold standard, 1999 December 1 (Folder 27: 3)
  - "An American Empire and the Geopolitics of 2005," paper, Security and Migrations in Mediterranean: A Prospective Vision workshop, Lisbon, Portugal, 2005 March 5 (Folder 27: 4)
- Political consulting file, 1975-1999
  Contains memoranda and speeches, largely relating to Bob Dole, Jack Kemp, and Ronald Reagan
  - Memoranda, 1993-1999
    - To Bob Dole, 1993-1996
      Includes related memoranda to others and enclosures
      - 1993 (Folder 27: 5)
      - 1994 (Folder 27: 6)
      - 1995 (Folder 27: 7)
      - 1996 (Folder 27: 8)
    - To Jack Kemp, 1996-1999
      - 1996 (Folder 27: 9)
      - 1998-1999 (Folder 27: 10)
  - Speeches written for others, 1975-1981
    - For Gerald Ford, on taxes, 1975 (Folder 28: 1)
    - For Jack Kemp, concerning his decision not to run for governor of New York, 1981 (Folder 28: 2)
    - For Ronald Reagan, 1980
      - "A Program to Stop Inflation,", 1980 (Folder 28: 3)
      - "Puerto Rico,", 1980 (Folder 28: 4)
- Writings by others, 1968-1998
  Contains articles and papers, largely relating to economics
  - Bandow, Doug, 1978-1979 (Folder 28: 5)
  - Brenner, Reuven, 1992-1998
    - 1992-1994 (Folder 28: 6)
    - 1995-1998 (Folder 28: 7)
  - Farrakhan, Louis, 1997-1998 (Folder 28: 8)
  - Mundell, Robert A., 1968-1985
    - 1968-1973 (Folder 28: 9)
    - 1985 (Folder 28: 10)
  - Reynolds, Alan, 1983-1989 (Folder 28: 11)
- Subject file, 1975-1993
  Contains clippings, correspondence, and pamphlets, largely relating to China, Puerto Rico, and the Russian Federation
  - China-Politics and government, 1995-1997 (Folder 28: 12)
  - Farrakhan, Louis, 1996-1998
    - 1996-1997 (Folder 28: 13)
    - 1998 (Folder 28: 14)
  - Federal Reserve System, 1994-1997 (Folder 29: 1)
  - Iraq-Politics and government, 1998 (Folder 29: 2)
  - Puerto Rico-Economic conditions, 1975-1985
    - 1975 (Folder 29: 3)
    - 1976-1977 (Folder 29: 4)
    - 1980-1985 (Folder 29: 5)
  - Reagan, Ronald, 1980 (Folder 29: 6)
  - Russian Federation Project, 1989-1992
    - 1989-1990 (Folder 29: 7)
    - 1991-1992 (Folder 29: 8)
  - Taxation, 1980-1993 (Folder 29: 9)
- CLOSED
  - Two compact discs containing electronic email messages of jwanniski@polyconomics.com account, 1996-2005 (Folder 30:)
    Use copies of PDF files of some messages available on workstation computer in Reading Room (for details, see above under heading Email messages)